#### **OLIVIER DEISS**

6 Rue de l'Enclos – 14112 Périers-Sur-Le-Dan – France +33 (0) 6 02 07 76 38 – olivier.deiss@gatech.edu http://olivierdeiss.com

- Candidate for a MSc. in Computer Science at Georgia Tech Lorraine
- Professional experience in software development and testing on large-scale projects (Eikon, ~20M lines of code)
- Experience in version controlling and development in teams with C++, Java and Javascript

# **EDUCATION**

SUMMARY

### GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - LORRAINE CAMPUS

Metz, FRA

Candidate for Master of Science in Computer Science

Aug. 2016 - Dec. 2017

• Specialization in Machine Learning, with courses in AI, machine learning, and algorithm design.

GPA: 4.00

• Research: set up a Hadoop cluster of five nodes for the analysis of rosbags (ROS) in C++ jobs.

SUPÉLEC

Metz, FRA

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2016

• Courses in algorithms & complexity, computer architecture and software engineering.

GPA: 3.93

# LYCÉE PIERRE CORNEILLE

Rouen, FRA
Sep. 2012 – Jun. 2014

Preparatory Classes

• Intensive program in advanced maths and physics

 $ep. \ 2012 - Jun. \ 2014$ Rank: 1/45

# **EXPERIENCES**

GOOGLE

Mountain View, CA, USA

Software Engineer Intern, Search, Android TV

Jan. 2017 - Apr. 2017

• Worked on integrating Google Assistant into Android TV, as well as improving the search results.

### THOMSON REUTERS

London, UK

Software Developer Intern, Eikon Financial Analysis

Jul. 2016 - Aug. 2016

- Turned error messages into selling opportunities (up to +\$2.3M per year) by implementing a *Polymer* component, easily embeddable in apps, which displays a list of available products when users try to access unauthorized content.
- Built demo apps to introduce the feature to existing customers, using *Node.js*, *Neo4j* and *Python* scripts, as well as unit tests with *Mocha/Chai*, and a documentation, ensuring a wide internal use of the component.
- My work has been shown to James Smith, CEO of Thomson Reuters, and won an internal innovation contest.

## INSTRUCTOR LIVE

London, UK

Full-Stack Developer Intern

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

- Implemented a new user type on the webserver, integrating the new business model on the back-end logic.
- Developed a new video player for the Android and Samsung Smart TV apps, supporting a new content provider.
- Designed a workout planner and a calendar module for the front-end on Angular.js, encouraging subscriptions.

## SELECTED PROJECTS

### **BRAIN-COMPUTER INTERFACE**

Metz, FRA

Research at Supélec

Nov. 2015 - Jun. 2016

- Led a research group through the development of software in C++ that performs real-time classification of brainwaves related to the hands, using machine learning and signal processing, achieving 70% of correct classification.
- Interpreted the algorithm output with a ROS interface, making it possible to pilot a robot by moving the hands.

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

- DigitScanner: implemented a feedforward neural network, achieving 98.24% of correct classification (MNIST).
- FFTOcean: implemented an FFT algorithm for the real-time simulation of ocean water in C++, with OpenGL.

# SKILLS, INTERESTS

Programming (advanced): C++, python, Java

Softwares: Git, LaTeX

Programming (intermediate): php, javascript Frameworks: Angular.js, Node.js, Polymer, Qt **Languages:** English (professional proficiency)

French (native)

**GRE:** 168/170 (Quant) - 158/170 (Verb) - 4/6 (Writing)

NewbieContest.org: - Rank: 192/41858 (Dec. 2016) - Online hacking, cracking, and coding challenges.

I practice badminton, hiking and biking, and I am always up for positive change: last year I switched to *Vim*, learned touch typing, and totally quit drinking sodas. This year I want to start running and to experiment with a biphasic sleep cycle. I keep exploring the world, and Asia is next on my list!